Voronetskyy Yevgen	
Paris, France	
Phone: +33.6.29.84.09.83	
Was born the 23 Novembre 1981, Ukraine.	

Summary

Java/J2EE software engineer. Information systems design and implementation. OOP/AOP. N-tiers architectures. RDBMS/SQL. Design patterns. UML. RUP, agile software development. Experience in the industrialization of development processes. European education. Master degree in Computer Science. 4 years of international experience (projects for IT-consulting, insurance and software companies). 21 IT-certifications from Brainbench system. Fluent french, good english, russian and ukrainian - native speaker. Purposeful and responsible. Professional ambition - become a software architect.

Education

	Teamlog Institute (Paris, France)
2008	Professional courses organized by Teamlog Institute. Effective
	communication, English courses (intermediate level)
2004-2005	University Paris-Est Marne-la-Vallée (Champs-sur-Marne, France)
	Master Degree in Computer Science. DESS « Communication, Network,
	Image », section Network (actual Master CS).
2005	Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers (CNAM) (Champs-sur-
	Marne, France)
	Enterprise managemenent course for engineers. Social Management
	course.
	Ukrainian State University of Chemical Engineering
1999-2004	(Dniepropetrovsk, Ukraine)
	Speciality « Specialized computer systems ». Master Degree in Computer
	Science, with honour (2004).

Work experience

July 2008 to Date	Company: Teamlog (Paris, France) Position: Technical lead Mission description: Participation in the design, development and management of the IT-projects (some on offshore mode). Architecture development, solving critical technical problems. Setup project infrastructure: SVN, builds, unit tests, Mantis, etc. Code revue. Participation in industrialization of IT-projects development(continuous integration, design/code quality, metrics). Conducting the technical interviews. Responsible for communication with customers. Technical audit for Java/J2EE projects (ISO-9126, Sonar, PMD, Cobertura, Metrics, SourceMonitor). Technologies: Java/J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, Quartz, Struts, JUnit, Servlets/JSP, JAAS, JAXB, decompiler JAD, MySQL, LDAP, Ant, Maven, TeamCity, DBUnit, Linux, RPM, PowerDesigner.
October 2006 - May 2008	Company: DVK-Tech (Paris, France) Position: Java/J2EE Software Engineer Mission description: Java/J2EE consulting and development for different companies. The list of projects done with DVK-Tech is presented below and marked by ***.
November 2007 - May 2008	Company: Générali (Saint-Denis, France) Position: Java/J2EE Software Engineer

	Mission description: Development of Java-based enterprise server. Technical design and implementation of different integration modules for connecting externs information systems. The development process is based on some industrial standards of the software building. Technologies: JAVA/J2EE, EJB, application server WebSphere 6.1, Oracle, SQL, MyEclipse, Rational Rose, UML. Advanced using of SQL language.
October 2007	Company: SMI-Mutuelle (Paris, France) Position: Java/J2EE Consultant Mission description: Audit of a web-application that represents the company business workflow. Analysis and documentation of the existing architecture with further recommendations for optimisation and evolution. Writing the technical documentation describing the development environment and deployment process. Technologies: Java/J2EE, Servlet, Java Service Wrapper, Winstone, Oracle 8; UML diagrams.
March 2007 - October 2007	Company: Mondial-Assistance (Paris, France) Position: Java/J2EE Software Engineer Mission description: Participation in the design and development of « e-commerce » projects. Persistence layer has been implemented with Hibernate and JDO (XCalia implementation). Bridge between business logic and presentation layer was developed according to MVC pattern on Struts framework. Web GUI-components development with AJAX. Architecture design and implementation of different application modules. Implementation of business logic layer. Technologies: Java/J2EE, Struts 1.3, Hibernate 3.0, JDO (Xcalia implementation), Servlet/JSP, JSTL, Tomcat 5.5, MySQL, Oracle, MS SQL Server, FreeMaker, Common-Controls, many librairies from Jakarta Commons.
October 2006- February 2007	Company: Web Agency DUKE (Paris, France) Position: Java/J2EE Software Engineer Mission description: Design and realization of web site "back-office" solutions based on 3-tier architecture; persistence, business object layer (POJO), deployment; logging, security and emailing modules. Developing of the security module for a web-application with Tomcat container managed security. Persistence layer implemented only with DAO's based on pure JDBC API. Programming the java-façades for Flash-based GUI-interface. Web GUI-components development with AJAX. Conception and realization of standalone application (server) aimed to survey the availability of internet sites. This application was developed with multithreading features as daemon for Linux Debian OS. Participation in projects architecture design. Technologies: Java/J2EE, JDBC, Servlet/JSP, Tomcat 5.5, MySQL 4.1, PostgreSQL, Log4j, Velocity, JSVC.
December 2005 - August 2006	Company: ISD - Information Systems Development (Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine) Position: Junior Java Software Engineer Mission description: Development of web-based time management system. Accomplished tasks: developing gui-components based on JSF; application server migration from WebSphere to JBoss; implementation of stresstest scripts with OpenSTA ans SCL language; application maintenance management. Technologies: application servers WebSphere and JBoss, RDBMS Oracle, Hibernate, Spring, JSF, JNDI.

	Company: LegitiName (Rumelange, Luxembourg)
	Position: .NET/C# Engineer
	Mission description: Responsible for product evolution "SiteAudit".
April 2005 -	Specification and implementation of core project functionality.
October 2005	Preparing technical documentation. Technologies : Programming on
	framework .NET, language C#, XML (XPath, XSD), ADO.NET, Microsoft
	SQL Server, librairies "Microsoft XMLDiff and XMLPatch 1.0" and
	"HtmlAgilityPack" by Simon Mournier.

Technical Skills

Operating systems	MS Windows 95/98/2000/XP/Vista; Linux (Debian/Mandrake).
Programming languages	Java , C# , Pascal, PHP. ;Java frameworks and librairies: Log4j, Spring, Struts, Hibernate, many sub-projets of Apache Commons, Velocity, iText, JSVC. XML (XSL, XPath, XSD), HTML(CSS, JavaScript).
Java/J2EE	Core Java, Application/web servers, JDBC, Servlets/JSP, JNDI, RMI, EJB, Web Services. Application/web servers: JBoss, WebSphere, Tomcat, Resin. Deep understanding of basis of distributed n-tier architecture: business objects (POJO and EJB), persistance, security issues, transactions, multithreading, logging.
RDBMS	ORACLE 9i/10g, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server 2000; SQL language.
Tools	Eclipse, NetBeans, Microsoft Visual Studio, JProfiler, ANT, Maven, CVS, SVN, SQuirreL, Toad, Far.
Software methodologies	Design Patterns (GoF+GRASP) , UML, Rational Unified Process, agile methodologies (with JUnit and continouos integretion server TeamCity).
Certifications	I have earned the following certificates from Brainbench system:

Spoken languages

Russian	Native speaker.
Ukrainian	Native speaker.
	Fluent. More than 10 years of experience. Having the following french
French	diplomas of the Common European Framework of References for
	languages: DELF B1, B2, B3, DALF C2.
English	Reading/writing – very good, oral expression – good.

Interests

Interests	Java, software design and implementation, Graphical User Interface (GUI) design and usability, geography, foreign languages.
Sports	Athletics, gymnastics, swimming, volley-ball.
Blog	http://yevgen-fr.blogspot.com - My personal technical blog in French about IT, programming, Java.